<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | OCS</title>
    <link>http://opencasestudies.github.io/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://opencasestudies.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://opencasestudies.github.io/img/icon.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>http://opencasestudies.github.io/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking for a Student to Join the OCS Team!</title>
      <link>http://opencasestudies.github.io/post/recruiting-student/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://opencasestudies.github.io/post/recruiting-student/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Johns Hopkins Data Science Lab is seeking a Master’s student to assist with a project to create interactive elements for existing data science/public health/statistics education material as part of the open case studies project (&lt;a href=&#34;https://opencasestudies.github.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://opencasestudies.github.io/&lt;/a&gt;). This role would also involve creating websites and packages in R to make our materials more accessible to others, as well as some research to assess the utility of our materials in the classroom. We have budgeted for financial support for this student, and this work could potentially be used as a thesis project. Please contact Carrie Wright (cwrigh60@jh.edu) if you are interested in learning more!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome Carrie Wright to OCS Team!</title>
      <link>http://opencasestudies.github.io/post/welcome-carrie-wright/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://opencasestudies.github.io/post/welcome-carrie-wright/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In September 2019, we welcomed &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencasestudies.github.io/authors/cwright/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Carrie Wright&lt;/a&gt; to the OCS Team as a Research Associate faculty in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://jhudatascience.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Johns Hopkins Data Science Lab&lt;/a&gt; working on building Open Case Studies.
She completed her postdoctoral fellowship at the Lieber Institute for Brain Development where she was a co-founder of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://research.libd.org/rstatsclub/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;LIBD rstats club&lt;/a&gt;.
We are all very excited to have her join the team and leverage her expertise in data analysis to building open case studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In just the last few months, she has revamped the website and is taking the lead on building 10 case studies focused on public health challenges funded by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bloomberg.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Bloomberg Philanthropies&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned over the next few months as we add new case studies!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Case Studies now have DOIs for citations!</title>
      <link>http://opencasestudies.github.io/post/case-studies-now-have-doi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://opencasestudies.github.io/post/case-studies-now-have-doi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Open Case Studies team is excited to announce
that case studies now have digital object identifier
(DOIs) associated with each case study that can be used
as a citation. If you use one of the case studies in your
classroom, we ask that you use the DOI to reference it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The OCS Team&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
